# Richard Job B

19 Ramakrishna Street, Moorthi nagar, Ullagarm, Chennai 600091 +91 9003287975 richardjob05@gmail.com



https://richardjob.me



Inkedin.com/in/richardjob



github.com/richardjob

#### **SUMMARY**

Adaptable Computer Applications major currently attending Madras Christian College, with 3 months of work experience. Freshworks Hackathon winner. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of application development, emerging technologies, and server architecture skills to successfully fill the Software Developer role at your company. Frequently praised as hard-working by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

# **EDUCATION** SKILLS

# **Bachelor of Computer Applications**

Madras Christian College, Chennai, India 2018 – 2021

#### **HSC - Computer Science**

Vyasa Vidyalaya Matriculation Higher Secondary School 2017 – 2018

# SSLC

Vyasa Vidyalaya Matriculation Higher Secondary School 2015 – 2016

# Express.js React.js Node.js

Java HTML/CSS

C#

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Associate Software Developer - Part Time**

Virtual Technologies

Clearwater, Florida, United States (Remote work) 07/2020 - Present

- Working in multiple roles of the company, gathering requirements and building a MVP.
- Cloud hosting and server side development with various Tech stacks.

#### **Web Development - Intern**

**Helping Hands** 

New Delhi, India (Remote work) 03/2020 - 06/2020

- Worked on the server side of the company jobs and career portal.
- Built a REST API using node.js for Job portal. Managed JWT authentication of user and admin.

## **CERTIFICATES**

C Programming

**AWS** 

Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB

Coursera

AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native

Coursera

**Docker Essentials** 

**IBM Cognitive Class** 

Learning Java

LinkedIn Learning

# Accomplishments

#### Freshworks Hackathon Winner

- Built a Integration between Freshdesk and Basecamp.
- Enabled Millions of users to access Basecamp without leaving Freshdesk.
- Increased productivity of employees by 50% by reducing the time in switching tabs.

#### JP Morgan Chase & Co. Virtual Experience Program Participant

- Participated in the open access Virtual Experience Program with InsideSherpa.
- Created an Interface with stock price data feed.
- Used JP Morgan Frameworks and tools.
- Visually Displayed data for traders.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

# **React Image Classifier**

- A Web based Image Classifier powered by Imagga API.
- A powerful back-end built with scalability in mind using Node.js.
- User authentication and storage is managed using Google Cloud and Firebase.
- The Front-end is developed using React.js, a Javascript library by using state management.

# **Guess IT (Android app)**

- Android number guessing game built using Java and Android Studio.
- The app generates a random number between the given Interval.
- A user has 10 attempts to guess the number.

#### Mars Man (Google Assistant Action)

- Under ongoing development and research.
- Built using Google Dialog flow and Actions SDK.
- A weather app for Mars.
- Made use of open source NASA API to retrieve real time information about Mars.